I'm just going to play a brief video clip.
سوف أعرض لكم مقطع فيديو قصير
Video:
الفيديو: 50,000 جنيه انجليزي
On the fifth of December 1985, a bottle of 1787 Lafitte was sold
في الخامس من ديسمبر عام 1985 ، قنينة من نبيذ "لافيت" من عام 1787 بيعت
for 105,000 pounds -- nine times the previous world record.
ب 105,000 جنيه انكليزي -- تسعة أضعاف الرقم القياسي العالمي السابق
The buyer
السيد فوربس
was Kip Forbes,
المشتري كان كيب فوربس
son of one of the most flamboyant millionaires of the 20th century.
ابن واحد من ألمع مليونيري القرن العشرين
The original owner of the bottle turned out to be
المالك الأصلي لقنينة النبيذ كان
one of the most enthusiastic wine buffs of the 18th century.
واحد من اكثر متذوقي النبيذ حماسة في القرن الثامن عشر
Château Lafitte is one of the greatest wines in the world,
" شاتو لافيت" هو واحد من أشهر الخمور في العالم
the prince of any wine cellar.
فهو كالأمير في أي قبو نبيذ
Benjamin Wallace: Now, that's about all the videotape that remains of an event
بنجامين والاس: الآن ، هذا الفيديو هو كل ما تبقى من الحادثة
that set off the longest-running mystery in the modern wine world.
التي أدت الى أطول غموض في عالم الخمور المعاصر
And the mystery existed because of a gentleman named Hardy Rodenstock.
وقد حدث هذا الغموض بسبب رجل يدعى هاردي رودنستوك
In 1985, he announced to his friends in the wine world
في عام 1985 ، قام هذا الرجل باخبار أصدقاءه في مجال النبيذ
that he had made this incredible discovery.
بأنه اكتشف شيئا مذهلا
Some workmen in Paris had broken through a brick wall,
بعض العمال في باريس أحدثوا ثقبا في جدار
and happened upon this hidden cache of wines --
والذي تصادف أنه مخبأ لنبيذ
apparently the property of Thomas Jefferson. 1787, 1784.
وعلى ما يبدو أنه مملوك لتوماس جيفرسون. 1787, 1784
He wouldn't reveal the exact number of bottles,
لم يكن يريد هذا الرجل أن يكشف عدد هذه القنينات بالضبط
he would not reveal exactly where the building was
لم يكن يريد هذا الرجل أن يكشف موقع البناية
and he would not reveal exactly who owned the building.
ولم يكن يريد هذا الرجل أن يكشف من هو مالك البناية
The mystery persisted for about 20 years.
واستمر هذا الغموض عشرون عاما
It finally began to get resolved in 2005 because of this guy.
وأخيرا بدأت خيوط هذا الغموض تتفكك في عام 2005 بسبب رجل
Bill Koch is a Florida billionaire who owns four of the Jefferson bottles,
بيل كوش مليونير من فلوريدا ويملك اربع قنينات من قنينات جيفرسون
and he became suspicious.
وأصبح يشك في أمر هذه القنينات
And he ended up spending over a million dollars and hiring ex-FBI
وانتهى به الأمر الى انفاق ما يزيد على مليون دولار والاستعانة بموظفين سابقين في مكتب التحقيقات الفيدرالي
and ex-Scotland Yard agents to try to get to the bottom of this.
وعملاء سابقين من اسكتلندا لحل هذا الغموض
There's now ample evidence that Hardy Rodenstock is a con man,
والآن هناك دليل واضح بأن هاردي رودنستوك رجل مخادع
and that the Jefferson bottles were fakes.
وأن قنينات جيفرسون مزيفة
But for those 20 years,
لكن خلال هذه العشرين سنة
an unbelievable number of really eminent and accomplished figures
عدد لا يصدق من الشخصيات المرموقة والبارعة
in the wine world were sort of drawn into the orbit of these bottles.
في عالم النبيذ انجرفت الى الهالة المحيطة بهذه القنينات
I think they wanted to believe that the most expensive bottle of wine
انا أعتقد أنهم يريدون أن يصدقوا أن أغلى قنينة نبيذ
in the world must be the best bottle of wine in the world,
في العالم يجب أن تكون أفضل قنينة نبيذ في العالم
must be the rarest bottle of wine in the world.
ويجب أن تكون أندر قنينة نبيذ في العالم
I became increasingly, kind of voyeuristically interested in the question of
لقد أصبحت بشكل متزايد ، نوعا ما مهووسا بالسؤال
you know, why do people spend these crazy amounts of money,
انتم تعلمون ، لماذا ينفق الناس هذه المبالغ المهولة من المال
not only on wine but on lots of things,
ليس على النبيذ فقط وإنما على الكثير من الأشياء
and are they living a better life than me?
وهل يعيشون حياة افضل مني؟
So, I decided to embark on a quest.
لهذا ، قررت ان أبدأ في البحث
With the generous backing of a magazine I write for sometimes,
بدعم سخي من مجلة أكتب لها في بعض الأحيان
I decided to sample the very best, or most expensive, or most coveted item
لقد قررت أن أختبر أفضل أو أغلى أو أكثر شيء جاذبية
in about a dozen categories,
في 12 مجموعة تقريبا
which was a very grueling quest, as you can imagine.
وقد كان البحث مرهقا ، كما تتصورون
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This was the first one.
هذا هو أول شيء
A lot of the Kobe beef that you see in the U.S. is not the real thing.
الكثير من اللحم البقري المسمى "كوبيه" الموجود في الولايات المتحدة ليس حقيقيا
It may come from Wagyu cattle,
يمكن أن يكون مصدره ماشية " واجيو "
but it's not from the original, Appalachian Hyogo Prefecture in Japan.
لكنه ليس أصليا من مقاطعة "هيوجو ابلاشين" اليابانية
There are very few places in the U.S. where you can try real Kobe,
هناك عدد قلبل من الأماكن في الولايات المتحدة حيث يمكن أن تجرب لحم "كوبيه" الحقيقي
and one of them is Wolfgang Puck's restaurant, Cut, in Los Angeles.
وأحد هذه الأماكن هو مطعم "وولفغانغ باك" في لوس انجلوس
I went there, and I ordered the eight-ounce rib eye for 160 dollars.
لقد ذهبت الى هناك وطلبت شريحة "ريب آي" وزنها 8 اونصات وسعرها 160 دولار
And it arrived, and it was tiny.
ووصلت الشريحة ، لقد كانت صغيرة
And I was outraged.
وكنت غاضبا
It was like, 160 dollars for this?
لقد كان مثل ، 160 دولار لهذا؟
And then I took a bite,
ثم أخذت لقمة
and I wished that it was tinier, because Kobe beef is so rich.
وتمنيت لو كانت أصغر ، لأن لحم "كوبيه" دسم جدا
It's like foie gras -- it's not even like steak.
انه مثل معجون كبد الأوز -- وليس مثل شرائح اللحم
I almost couldn't finish it.
بالكاد استطعت اكمالها
I was really happy when I was done.
لقد كنت سعيدا عندما انتهيت
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, the photographer who took the pictures for this project
الآن ، المصور الذي التقط الصور لهذا المشروع
for some reason posed his dog in a lot of them,
لبعض الأسباب جعل كلبه يظهر في الكثير منها
so that's why you're going to see this recurring character.
لهذا سوف يتكرر ظهور هذه الشخصية
Which, I guess, you know, communicates to you
التي ، كما أعتقد ، توضح لكم
that I did not think that one was really worth the price.
بأنني لا أعتقد ان هذه تستحق هذا السعر
White truffles.
الكمأ الأبيض
One of the most expensive luxury foods by weight in the world.
واحد من أغلى وأفخم الأطعمة في العالم التي تباع بالوزن
To try this, I went to a Mario Batali restaurant
لتجربة هذا ، ذهبت إلى مطعم "ماريو باتالي"
in Manhattan -- Del Posto.
في ديل بوستو ، منهاتن
The waiter, you know, came out with the white truffle knob
جاءني النادل ، كما تعلمون ، بقطعة من الكمأ الأبيض
and his shaver, and he shaved it onto my pasta and he said, you know,
و مبشرة ، و أخذ يبشرها فوق المعكرونة وقال ، كما تعلمون
"Would Signore like the truffles?"
"هل السيد يحب الكمأ؟"
And the charm of white truffles is in their aroma.
روعة وسحر الكمأ في شذاه
It's not in their taste, really. It's not in their texture.
وليس في مذاقه ، في الواقع . وليس في ملمسه
It's in the smell.
انما في رائحته
These white pearlescent flakes hit the noodles,
هذه الرقائق البيضاء اللامعة كاللؤلؤ تصطدم بالمعكرونة
this haunting, wonderful, nutty, mushroomy smell wafted up.
وهذه الرائحة الرائعة التي لا تنسى والتي لها نكهة الجوز والمشروم تنبعث
10 seconds passed and it was gone.
عشر ثواني تمر ثم تتلاشى الرائحة
And then I was left with these little ugly flakes on my pasta that,
ثم أبقى أنا مع هذه الرقائق البشعة على معكرونتي التي
you know, their purpose had been served,
كما تعلمون ، خدمت هدفها
and so I'm afraid to say that this was also a disappointment to me.
وأنا أخشى أن أقول أن هذا كان مخيبا لآمالي أيضا
There were several -- several of these items were disappointments.
كان هناك العديد -- العديد من هذه الأشياء كان مخيبا للآمال
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Yeah.
نعم
The magazine wouldn't pay for me to go there.
المجلة لم تدفع لي لأذهب إلى هناك
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
They did give me a tour, though.
مع ذلك ، أعطوني جولة
And this hotel suite is 4,300 square feet.
وهذا الجناح الفندقي مساحته 4,300 قدم مربع
It has 360-degree views.
يقدم اطلالة مداها 360 درجة
It has four balconies.
فيه اربع بلكونات
It was designed by the architect I.M. Pei.
صممه المعماري أي أم بيه
It comes with its own Rolls Royce and driver.
مع سيارة رولز رويس خاصة به وسائق
It comes with its own wine cellar that you can draw freely from.
وقبو نبيذ تستطيع أن تأخذ منه بحرية
When I took the tour, it actually included some Opus One, I was glad to see.
وكان يحتوي على نبيذ "أوبس ون" أثناء جولتي . لقد كنت سعيدا لرؤيته
30,000 dollars for a night in a hotel.
30,000 دولار لليلة واحدة في فندق
This is soap that's made from silver nanoparticles,
هذه صابونة مصنوعة من جزيئات صغيرة جدا من الفضة (نانو جزيئات)
which have antibacterial properties.
مضادة للبكتيريا
I washed my face with this this morning in preparation for this.
غسلت وجهي بها هذا الصباح عند التحضير لهذا العرض
And it, you know, tickled a little bit and it smelled good,
و كما تعلمون ، لقد دغدغتني قليلا وكانت رائحتها جيدة
but I have to say that nobody here
لكن يجب أن أقول أنه لا أحد هنا
has complimented me on the cleanliness of my face today.
أثنى على نظافة وجهي اليوم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But then again, nobody has complimented me on the jeans I'm wearing.
ولكن أيضا ، لا أحد أثنى على الجينز الذي أرتديه
These ones GQ did spring for -- I own these -- but I will tell you,
والذي أعطتني اياه مجلة "جي كيو" -- أنا أمتلك هذا الجينز -- لكن سوف أخبركم
not only did I not get a compliment from any of you,
ليس فقط أنني لم أحصل على أي اطراء منكم
I have not gotten a compliment from anybody
بل لم أحصل على اطراء من أي أحد على الاطلاق
in the months that I have owned and worn these.
في الأشهر التي لبست فيها هذا الجينز
I don't think that whether or not you're getting a compliment
لا أعتقد أن الحصول على اطراء أو عدم الحصول عليه
should be the test of something's value,
يجب أن يكون مقياسا لقيمة شيء ما
but I think in the case of a fashion item, an article of clothing,
لكني أعتقد انه في حالة الموضة ، كقطعة من الملابس
that's a reasonable benchmark.
فإنه مؤشر منطقي
That said, a lot of work goes into these.
مع ذلك ، هذا الجينز تطلب الكثير من العمل
They are made from handpicked organic Zimbabwean cotton
انه مصنوع من قطن عضوي مقطوف يدويا من زيمبابوي
that has been shuttle loomed
تم غزله ونسجه
and then hand-dipped in natural indigo 24 times.
ثم صبغ بالغمس يدويا في الصبغ الأزرق النيلي الطبيعي 24 مرة
But no compliments.
لكن لا اطراء
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Thank you.
شكرا لكم
Armando Manni is a former filmmaker who makes this olive oil
المخرج السابق أرماندو ماني هو الذي ينتج زيت الزيتون هذا
from an olive that grows on a single slope in Tuscany.
من الزيتون الذي ينمو في منحدر معين في توسكاني
And he goes to great lengths to protect the olive oil from oxygen and light.
وقد ذهب إلى أبعد الحدود لحماية زيت الزيتون من الأوكسجين والضوء
He uses tiny bottles, the glass is tinted,
وهو يستخدم قنينات صغيرة جدا ، زجاجها معتم
he tops the olive oil off with an inert gas.
ويملأ باقي القنينة بغاز خامل
And he actually -- once he releases a batch of it,
كما أنه في الواقع -- عندما يصدر دفعة من الزيت
he regularly conducts molecular analyses and posts the results online,
يقوم باجراء تحليل جزيئي بانتظام وينشر النتائج في الانترنت
so you can go online and look at your batch number
بحيث أنه من خلال الانترنت ورقم التشغيلة
and see how the phenolics are developing,
يمكنك أن ترى تكون مشتقات الفينول
and, you know, gauge its freshness.
و كما تعلمون ، تحدد جودة زيت الزيتون وكم هو طازج
I did a blind taste test of this with 20 people and five other olive oils.
وقد قمت باختبار تذوق مع مجموعة من عشرين شخص لتقييم الزيت مع خمسة أنواع أخرى بطريقة التعمية
It tasted fine. It tasted interesting.
لقد كان مذاقه جيدا ، وممتعا أيضا
It was very green, it was very peppery.
لونه أخضر مركز ، وطعمه حار جدا
But in the blind taste test, it came in last.
لكن في اختبار التذوق ، حل في المركز الأخير
The olive oil that came in first was actually a bottle of
زيت الزيتون الذي جاء في المركز الأول كان في الحقيقة قنينة من
Whole Foods 365 olive oil which had been oxidizing next to my stove
زيت زيتون "هول فودز 365" الذي يتأكسد بجانب موقدي
for six months.
لمدة ستة أشهر
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
A recurring theme is that a lot of these things are from Japan --
الفكرة المتكررة في الكثير من هذه الأشياء هو أنها جاءت من اليابان --
you'll start to notice.
سوف تبدؤون بملاحظة ذلك
I don't play golf, so I couldn't actually road test these,
أنا لا ألعب الجولف ، لهذا لم أستطع في الواقع اختبار هذه
but I did interview a guy who owns them.
لكنني أجريت مقابلة مع شخص يمتلكهم
Even the people who market these clubs -- I mean, they'll say
حتى الأشخاص الذين يبيعون عصي الجولف هذه -- أنا أقصد أنهم سوف يقولون
these have four axis shafts which minimize loss of club speed
أن لها أربعة أعمدة محورية تقلل من تناقص سرعة عصى الجولف
and thereby drive the ball farther -- but they'll say, look, you know,
وبالتالي تدفع الكرة لمسافة أبعد -- لكنهم سوف يقولون ، انظر
you're not getting 57,000 dollars worth of performance from these clubs.
أنت لن تحصل على أداء يستحق دفع 57,000 دولار لعصي الجولف هذه
You're paying for the bling,
أنت تدفع مقابل التباهي
that they're encrusted with gold and platinum.
لأنها مطلية بالذهب والبلاتين
The guy who I interviewed who owns them did say
الشخص الذي أجريت معه المقابلة ويمتلك عصي الجولف تلك قال
that he's gotten a lot of pleasure out of them, so ...
بأنه يستمتع بها كثيرا ، لهذا ...
Oh, yeah, you know this one?
أوه ، نعم ، أنتم تعرفون هذه؟
This is a coffee made from a very unusual process.
هذه القهوة مصنوعة بطريقة غير اعتيادية
The luwak is an Asian Palm Civet.
" اللواك " هو سنور الزباد الآسيوي
It's a cat that lives in trees,
وهو قط يعيش على الأشجار
and at night it comes down and it prowls the coffee plantations.
وخلال الليل ، ينزل الى الأرض ويتجول في مزارع القهوة
And apparently it's a very picky eater and it, you know,
والذي يظهر أنه آكل صعب الارضاء ، حيث أنه
hones in on only the ripest coffee cherries.
يتجه نحو أنضج حبوب القهوة فقط
And then an enzyme in its digestive tract leeches into the beans,
ثم الانزيمات في جهازه الهضمي تؤثر (تحلل جزئيا) هذه الحبوب
and people with the unenviable job of collecting these cats' leavings
والأشخاص الذين يقومون بوظيفة لا يحسدون عليها في جمع فضلات هذه القطط
then go through the forest collecting the, you know, results
يذهبون بعد ذلك الى الغابة ، كما تعلمون ، ليجمعون المحصول
and processing it into coffee -- although you actually can buy it
الذي يعالج ليصبح هذه القهوة على الرغم من أنك تستطيع في الواقع شراء
in the unprocessed form.
المادة الخام
That's right.
هذا صحيح
Unrelatedly --
من دون أن يكون هناك علاقة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Japan is doing crazy things with toilets.
هناك صرعات مجنونة للمراحيض في اليابان
There is now a toilet that has an MP3 player in it.
الآن هناك مرحاض مزود بمشغل "MP3"
There's one with a fragrance dispenser.
هناك واحد مع معطر جو
There's one that actually analyzes the contents of the bowl
وهناك واحد في الواقع يحلل محتوى المرحاض
and transmits the results via email to your doctor.
وينقل النتائج الى طبيبك عبر البريد الالكتروني
It's almost like a home medical center --
انه مثل مركز طبي في المنزل تقريبا
and that is the direction that Japanese toilet technology is heading in.
ونحو هذا الاتجاه تتحرك تكنولوجيا المراحيض في اليابان
This one does not have those bells and whistles,
هذا لا يحتوي على أجراس وصفارات
but for pure functionality it's pretty much the best -- the Neorest 600.
لكن من حيث الأداء يعتبر الأفضل -- "نيورورست 600 "
And to try this -- I couldn't get a loaner,
ولتجربة هذا -- لم أستطع العثور على من يعيرني اياه
but I did go into the Manhattan showroom of the manufacturer, Toto,
لكنني ذهبت الى صالة العرض للصانع توتو في منهاتن
and they have a bathroom off of the showroom that you can use, which I used.
والتي تحتوي على حمام في جانب صالة العرض و تستطيع استخدامه ، وقد استخدمته
It's fully automated -- you walk towards it, and the seat lifts.
انه اتوماتيكي بالكامل -- عندما تمشي باتجاهه ، يفتح غطاء المرحاض
The seat is preheated.
ويسخن مقعد المرحاض
There's a water jet that cleans you.
هناك مضخة ماء لتنظيفك
There's an air jet that dries you.
وهناك مضخة هواء لتجفيفك
You get up, it flushes by itself.
عندما تنهض ، ينطلق السيفون من نفسه
The lid closes, it self-cleans.
ويغلق غطاء المرحاض ، إنه ذاتي التنظيف
Not only is it a technological leap forward,
انه ليس فقط قفزة تكنولوجية للأمام
but I really do believe it's a bit of a cultural leap forward.
ولكني أعتقد أنه نوعا ما قفزة حضارية للأمام
I mean, a no hands, no toilet paper toilet.
أنا أقصد أنه ليس هناك حاجة لاستخدام اليدين أو ورق التواليت
And I want to get one of these.
وأنا أريد أن أحصل على واحد من هذه المراحيض
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This was another one I could not get a loaner of.
هذا شيء آخر لم أستطع أن أجد من يعيرني اياه
Tom Cruise supposedly owns this bed.
يفترض أن توم كروز يملك هذا السرير
There's a little plaque on the end that, you know,
هناك رقعة (لوحة) في الطرف
each buyer gets their name engraved on it.
ينقش عليها اسم كل مشتري
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
To try this one, the maker of it let me and my wife
لتجربة هذا ، سمح المنتج لي ولزوجتي
spend the night in the Manhattan showroom.
بقضاء ليلة في صالة العرض في منهاتن
Lights glaring in off the street,
حيث الأضواء ساطعة في الخارج
and we had to hire a security guard and all these things.
واضطررنا لتعيين حارس أمن وما إلى ذلك
But anyway, we had a great night's sleep.
لكن على أي حال ، حصلنا على نوم جيد
And you spend a third of your life in bed.
نحن نقضي ثلث عمرنا نائمين
I don't think it's that bad of a deal.
لا أعتقد أنها صفقة سيئة الى هذا الحد
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This was a fun one.
هذه كانت ممتعة
This is the fastest street-legal car in the world
هذه أسرع سيارة في العالم قيادتها قانونية في الشوارع
and the most expensive production car.
وأغلى سيارة تم انتاجها
I got to drive this with a chaperone from the company,
لقد قدت هذه السيارة برفقة مرشد من الشركة
a professional race car driver,
سائق سيارات سباق محترف
and we drove around the canyons outside of Los Angeles
وقدنا حول الوديان في لوس أنجلوس
and down on the Pacific Coast Highway.
وعلى طريق ساحل المحيط الهادىء السريع
And, you know, when we pulled up to a stoplight
وعندما نتوقف عند اشارة المرور
the people in the adjacent cars kind of gave us respectful nods.
يقوم الناس في السيارات المجاورة بما يشبه بايماءة احترام لنا
And it was really amazing.
وقد كان الوضع حقا مذهلا
It was such a smooth ride.
وكانت القيادة انسيابية وسلسة
Most of the cars that I drive, if I get up to 80 they start to rattle.
في أغلب السيارات التي قدتها ، اذا وصلت سرعة السيارة الى 80 فانها تبدأ في الاهتزاز
I switched lanes on the highway and the driver, this chaperone, said,
لقد غيرت الحارة في الطريق السريع وقال لي السائق المرشد
"You know, you were just going 110 miles an hour."
"هل تعلم ، أنت تقود بسرعة 110 ميل في الساعة فقط"
And I had no idea that I was one of those obnoxious people
ولم تكن لدي أي فكرة أنني أصبحت من هؤلاء الناس البغيضين
you occasionally see weaving in and out of traffic,
الذين تشاهدهم في بعض الأحيان يتمايلون في السير بين الحارات في الزحمة
because it was just that smooth.
لأن قيادة هذه السيارة كانت سلسة
And if I was a billionaire, I would get one.
ولو كنت بليونير ، لاشتريت واحدة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This is a completely gratuitous video I'm just going to show
هذا الفيديو لا مبرر له ، أنا فقط أريد أن أعرض
of one of the pitfalls of advanced technology.
واحدة من مشاكل التكنولوجيا المتقدمة
This is Tom Cruise arriving at the "Mission: Impossible III" premiere.
هذا توم كروز يصل للعرض الأول لفيلم " مهمة مستحيلة : الجزء الثالث"
When he tries to open the door,
عندما حاول أن يفتح الباب
you could call it "Mission: Impossible IV."
يمكن أن تسمي هذا " المهمة المستحيلة الرابعة "
There was one object that I could not get my hands on,
هناك شيء واحد لم أستطع الحصول عليه
and that was the 1947 Cheval Blanc.
وهو نبيذ " شافيل بلانك ، 1947 "
The '47 Cheval Blanc is probably the most mythologized wine of the 20th century.
نبيذ " شافيل بلانك ، 1947 " هو أكثر نبيذ أسطوري في القرن العشرين على الأرجح
And Cheval Blanc is kind of an unusual wine for Bordeaux
و "شافيل بلانك " هو نوعا ما نبيذ استثنائي من بوردو
in having a significant percentage of the Cabernet Franc grape.
حيث يحتوي على نسبة معتبرة من عنب كابرنت الفرنسي
And 1947 was a legendary vintage,
وصنف 1947 يعتبر اسطوري عتيق الطراز
especially in the right bank of Bordeaux.
وخصوصا في الجهة اليمنى من بوردو
And just together, that vintage and that chateau took on this aura
بما أنه عتيق وفرنسي في نفس الوقت فقد أعطاه ذلك هذه الهالة
that eventually kind of gave it this cultish following.
والتي أدت الى هذا الاعجاب الشديد
But it's 60 years old.
لكن عمر هذا النبيذ ستين عاما
There's not much of it left.
ولم يتبق منه الكثير
What there is of it left you don't know if it's real --
وما تبقى منه ، لا تعلم ان كان حقيقيا
it's considered to be the most faked wine in the world.
انه يعتبر اكثر الخمور عرضة للتزييف في العالم
Not that many people are looking to pop open
ليس هناك الكثبر من الناس الذين يتطلعون الى فتح
their one remaining bottle for a journalist.
زجاجة النبيذ الوحيدة المتبقية لديهم لصحفي
So, I'd about given up trying to get my hands on one of these.
لذلك تخليت عن فكرة المحاولة للحصول على واحدة من هذه الزجاجات
I'd put out feelers to retailers, to auctioneers,
لقد قدمت أسئلة واستفسارات الى التجار ومنسقي المزادات
and it was coming up empty.
لكن من دون فائدة
And then I got an email from a guy named Bipin Desai.
ثم تلقيت بريد الكتروني من رجل يدعى "بيبن ديساي"
Bipin Desai is a U.C. Riverside theoretical physicist
بيبن ديساي فيزيائي من قسم الفيزياء النظرية في جامعة كاليقورنيا
who also happens to be the preeminent organizer of rare wine tastings,
وهو أيضا المنظم البارز لجلسات التذوق لأندر أنواع النبيذ
and he said, "I've got a tasting coming up
يقول فيه بأنه سينظم جلسة تذوق
where we're going to serve the '47 Cheval Blanc."
وسوف يقدمون فيها " شافيل بلانك 47 "
And it was going to be a double vertical --
وقد كانت تجربة مزدوجة
it was going to be 30 vintages of Cheval Blanc,
سوف يكون هناك 30 نوع عتيق من " شافيل بلانك "
and 30 vintages of Yquem.
و 30 نوع عتيق من " ييكام "
And it was an invitation you do not refuse.
وقد كانت دعوة لا تستطيع رفضها
I went.
لقد ذهبت
It was three days, four meals.
لمدة ثلاثة أيام ، مع 4 وجبات
And at lunch on Saturday, we opened the '47.
وفي غداء يوم السبت ، فتحنا زجاجة " 47 "
And you know, it had this fragrant softness,
كان لها اريج لطيف
and it smelled a little bit of linseed oil.
ورائحة تشبه رائحة زيت الكتان نوعا ما
And then I tasted it, and it,
ثم تذوقته ، وكان
you know, had this kind of unctuous, porty richness,
زيتي غني مثل نبيذ " بورت "
which is characteristic of that wine --
وهذا ما يميز هذا النبيذ
that it sort of resembles port in a lot of ways.
والذي يشبه نبيذ " بورت " في كثير من الوجوه
There were people at my table who thought it was, you know, fantastic.
وقد اعتقد بعض الأشخاص الجالسين معي على الطاولة بأنه رائع
There were some people who were a little less impressed.
وهناك اخرين كانوا اقل تاثرا
And I wasn't that impressed.
وأنا لم أتاثر لهذه الدرجة
And I don't -- call my palate a philistine palate --
أنا لا أعتبر نفسي خبير في تذوق النبيذ
so it doesn't necessarily mean something that I wasn't impressed,
لهذا رأيي لا يعتبر مقياس مهم
but I was not the only one there who had that reaction.
لكني لم أكن الوحيد الذي كان له هذا الشعور
And it wasn't just to that wine.
ولم يكن شعوري هكذا لهذا النبيذ فقط
Any one of the wines served at this tasting,
لو أن أي نبيذ من الذين قدموا خلال جلسق التذوق
if I'd been served it at a dinner party, it would have been, you know,
لو قدم لي خلال حفلة عشاء ، لكان يمكن أن يكون
the wine experience of my lifetime, and incredibly memorable.
تجربة مهمة في حياتي ، وذكرى لا تنسى
But drinking 60 great wines over three days,
لكن شرب 60 نوع رائع من النبيذ خلال 3 أيام
they all just blurred together,
جعلهم يختلطون مع بعضهم
and it became almost a grueling experience.
وأصبحت التجربة نوعا ما مرهقة
And I just wanted to finish by mentioning a very interesting study
واود ان أنهي حديثي بالاشارة الى دراسة مشوقة جدا
which came out earlier this year from some researchers at Stanford and Caltech.
أجراها باحثين في ستانفورد و كالتك في وقت سابق هذه السنة
And they gave subjects the same wine,
حيث أعطي الأشخاص نفس النبيذ
labeled with different price tags.
ولكنه معلم ببطاقات ذات أسعار مختلفة
A lot of people, you know,
الكثير من الناس ، كما تعلمون ،
said that they liked the more expensive wine more --
قالوا أنهم يفضلون النبيذ الأغلى أكثر
it was the same wine, but they thought it was a different one
لقد كان نفس النبيذ ، لكنهم اعتقدوا أنه نوع أخر
that was more expensive.
أغلى ثمنا
But what was unexpected was that these researchers did
لكن الغير متوقع هو أن هؤلاء الباحثين قاموا
MRI brain imaging while the people were drinking the wine,
باجراء تصوير رنين مغناطيسي للمخ بينما كان هؤلاء الأشخاص يشربون النبيذ
and not only did they say they enjoyed the more expensively labeled wine more --
ليس فقط قال هؤلاء الأشخاص أنهم استمتعوا بالنبيذ المعلم بأنه أغلى أكثر
their brain actually registered as experiencing more pleasure
أدمغتهم في الواقع سجلت التجربة كأكثر امتاعا
from the same wine when it was labeled with a higher price tag.
لنفس النبيذ عندما علم ببطاقة سعر أعلى
Thank you.
شكرا لكم